Guide to the Yale Divinity School Faculty Writings and Publications
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Faculty M-W
  - Minear, Paul S.
    - Articles and Chapters
      - The Morphology of a Proverb, Anglican Theological Review, XXI/4, Oct 1939, pp. 282-292. (Box 58)
      - The Mystery of Baptism, Religion in Life, Spring 1951, pp. 225-235. (Box 58)
      - The Needle's Eye: a Study in Form Criticism, Jour. of Biblical Literature, LXI Part III, 1942, pp. 157-169. (Box 58)
      - New Every Morning. Bible Study from 2nd Assembly of WCC, 1954, pp. 5-31. (Box 58)
      - New Starting Point: Church Renewal and Social Renewal, Interpretation, XIX/1, Jan 1965, pp. 3-15. (Box 58)
      - The New Testament: Freedom and Self-Discipline, in The Bible and Alcohol and Drugs: A Study Guide, with Walter Brueggemann, 1978. (Box 58)
      - The New Testament Witness and Civilization, Theology Today, 5, 1948, pp. 340-349. (Box 58)
      - 1984: A Biblical Scholar Looks at Orwell's Novel, Reflection, 81/3, Apr 1984, pp. 7-9. (Box 58)
      - A Note on Luke 17:7-10, Jour. of Biblical Lit., 1974, pp. 82- 87. (Box 58)
      - A Note on Luke xxii 36, Novum Testamentum, Vii/2, Mar 1964, pp. 128-134. (Box 58)
      - Oekumenischer Beitrag zur Pneumatlogie, in Unterwegs zur Einheit, J. R. Brantschen and P. Selvatico, eds., 1980, pp. 791-802. (Box 59)
      - The Old and the New in the Church. World Council Commission on Faith and Order. Minneapolis: Augsburg Publishing House. 1961. Preface, pp.7-9. (Box 59)
      - On Building the Tombs of the Prophets, Ends and Odds, Study Papers from the Anglican Archbishopric in Jerusalem, June 1971, pp. 1-4. (Box 59)
      - Ontology and Ecclesiology in the Apocalypse, New Testament Studies, 13, pp. 89-105. (Box 59)
      - The Original Functions of John 21, Jour. of Biblical Literature, 102/1 1983, pp. 85-9. (Box 59)
      - Paul's Apostolic Call: Some Tangential Conjectures, Theology in Scotland, VI/2, Autumn 1999, pp. 5-30. (Box 54)
      - Paul's Missionary Dynamic, Hyde Lecture on Foreign Missions, Andover Newton Bulletin, 36/3, 1944, pp. 2-11. (Box 59)
      - Paul's Teaching on the Eucharist in First Corinthians, Worship 44/2, Feb 1970, pp. 83-92. (Box 59)
      - The Peril in Modernizing the Gospel, Encounter, 23/2, Spring 1962, pp. 190-195. (Box 59)
      - The Person and Work of Jesus, (International Lesson Series), Adult Bible Studies, 14/3, Mar-May 1982, pp. 9-95. (Box 59)
      - Petulance or Penitence, In Context (YDS), VIII/1, Winter 1958, pp. 5-6. (Box 59)
      - A Preface to the New Testament, [unidentified source], 7 p., n.d. (Box 59)
      - Propheten Gottes: das Wesen ihrer Berufung, in ökumenische Theologie in den Herausforderungen der Gegenwart, K. Gerschwiler et al, eds., pp. 175-191. (Box 59)
      - The Relevance of the Message for Our Day, Jour. of Bible and Religion, May 1942, pp. 88-92. (Box 59)
      - The Religion of Jesus and Social Change, pp. 2-58. (Box 59)
      - Report on Christ and the Church. Fourth World Conference on Faith and Order. Montreal, Canada. July 12-26, 1963. 62 pgs (Box 59)
      - Response to "The Eschaton", Spectrum: a Quarterly Journal of the Association of Adventist Forums, 5/1, 1973, pp. 32- 39. (Box 59)
      - The Resurrection of Jesus, Religion in Life, IX/2, Spring 1940, pp. 174-181. (Box 59)
      - Revelation, Adult Leader, 14/4, Jun-Aug 1982, pp. 23-26. (Box 59)
      - Revelation and the Knowledge of the Church, Dudleian Lecture, 1953-54, Harvard Divinity Bulletin, pp. 21-37., 1953-1954 (Box 59)
      - The Salt of the Earth, Interpretation, 51 no 1 Ja 1997, p 31- 41. (Box 54)
      - Salvation in the Apocalypse, Risk, 9/3, 1973, pp. 78-79. (Box 60)
      - Scholarship and Churchmanship (tribute to N. A. Dahl), Reflection, Apr 1980. (Box 60)
      - The Seventh Trumpet, of The Hallelujah Chorus, Worship, 78 no 1 Ja 2004, p 24-35. (Box 54)
      - The Significance of Civilization According to the Bible, Theology Today, V/3, Oct 1948, pp. 327-357. (Box 60)
      - The Significance of the Oberlin Conference, The Ecumenical Review, X/2, Jan 1958, pp. 121-126. (Box 60)
      - Some Glimpses of Luke in Sacramental Theology, Worship, 44/6, Jun-Jul, 1970, pp. 322-333. (Box 54)
      - Some Pauline Thoughts on Dying: a Study of 2 Corinthians, From Faith to Faith; Essays in Honor of Donald G. Miller, Pickwick Press, 1979 pp. 91-106. (Box 60)
      - Some Ruthless Attacks upon the Proposed Confession. Typescript, n.d. (Box 60)
      - Some Yesterdays with Raymond Morris, Reflections, 86/2, Summer-Fall 1991, pp. 20-22. (Box 60)
      - The Structure of Church and Society in the Light of the New Testament, The Student World, No. 1, 1959, pp.2-24. (Box 54)
      - Thanksgiving As a Synthesis of the Temporal and the Eternal, Anglican Theological Review, XXXVIII/1, Jan 1956, pp. 4-14. (Box 60)
      - Time and the Kingdom, Jour. of Religion, Apr 1944, pp. 77- 88. (Box 60)
      - The Time of Hope in the New Testament, Scottish Journal of Theology, Dec 1953, pp. 337-361. (Box 60)
      - To Ask and to Receive: Some Clues to Johannine Ontology, Intergerini Parietes Septum, Festschrift for M. Barth, 1981, pp. 227-250. (Box 60)
      - The Transcendence of God and Biblical Hermeneutics, The Catholic Theological Soc. of America: Proceedings of the 23rd Annual Convention, June 1968, pp. 1-19. (Box 60)
      - The Transmission of Faith Through Biblical Forms of Communication, Jour. of Religious Thought, IV/2, Spr-Summer 1947, pp. 136-151. (Box 60)
      - Two Saints...Almost, Yale Divinity News, 61/3, Mar 1964, pp. 5-6. (Box 60)
      - Two Secrets, Two Disclosures, Horizons in Biblical Theology, 29 no 1 2007, p 75-85. (Box 54)
      - The Vocation of the Church: Some Exegetical Clues, Missiology, 5, 1977, pp. 13-37. (Box 60)
      - Wanted: An Exegetical Realism, Theology Today, 59 no 2 Jl 2002, p 178-189. (Box 54)
      - "We Don't Know Where..." John 20:2, Interpretation, XXX/2, Apr 1976, pp. 125-139. (Box 60)
      - When Jesus Saw the Crowds, Expository Times, 116 no 3 D 2004, p 73-78. (Box 54)
      - The World Council and the Churches Called Congregational, Bulletin of the Congregational Library, 5/3, May, 1954, pp. 4-11. (Box 60)
      - The Wounded Beast, Jour. of Biblical Literature, 1953, pp. 93-101. (Box 60)
      - Writing on the Ground: The Puzzle in John 8:1-11, Horizons in Biblical Theology, 13 no 1 Je 1991, p 23-37. (Box 54)
      - Yes or No: The Demand for Honesty in the Early Church, Novum testamentum, 13 no 1 Ja 1971, p 1-13. (Box 54)
    - Book Reviews by Minear
      - Boring, M. Eugene. Revelation. Interpretation Commentary, Princeton Seminary Bulletin, XI/2 1990. And Midstream, XXX/1 January 1991. (Box 60)
      - Caird, G. B. The Revelation of St. John the Divine, Jour. of Biblical Literature, pp. 230-232., n.d. (Box 60)
      - Kierkegaard, S. On Authority and Revelation (trans. by W. Lowrie), The Review of Religion, XX/3-4, Mar 1956, pp. 203-207. (Box 60)
      - Reicke, Bo. The Epistles of James, Peter and Jude, (The Anchor Bible Series) Journal of Biblical Literature, pp. 181- 184. (Box 60)
      - Pelikan, Jaroslav. Bach Among the Theologians, American Bach Society Newsletter, Jun 1988, p.3. (Box 60)
      - Theissen, Gerd. The Shadow of the Galilean: The Quest of the Historical Jesus in Narrative Form(trans.by J. Bowden), Interpretation, Jan 1989, pp. 90-92. (Box 60)
      - Wilder, Amos Niven. The Language of the Gospel:Early Christian Rhetoric, The Christian Scholar, XLVIII/1, Spring 1965, pp. 72-74. (Box 60)
    - Unpublished writings
      - Catholicity; Catholicity and Apostolicity (Study Document prepared by the Joint Theological Commission, World Council of Churches (Box 54)
      - The Constitution on Divine Revelation: A Protestant Point of View (from consultation at Notre Dame University) (Box 54)
      - Day of Ecumenism, Boston College, 1965. (Box 54)
      - The Development of Interconfessional Research, National Workshop on Christian Unity, Baltimore, 1964. (Box 54)
      - An Exegetical Exploration of 2 Corinthians 5:14-21, New England Hermeneutics Group, 1966. (Box 54)
      - Interconfessional Research and the Theological Seminary, Boston University School of Theology (Box 54)
      - Next Steps in Ecumenism - Tentative Draft of Remarks, 1968. (Box 54)
      - The Unity of the Church or the Church of the Unity, Ecumenical Institute, Bossey, 1961. (Box 54)
      - Vatican II and Non-Catholic Theologicans (Box 54)
      - The Visible Church in the Pauline Writings, Roman Catholic-Protestant Colloquium, n.d. (Box 54)
      - Bible studies and writings from ecumenical gatherings, including WCC (Box 54)
    - About Minear
      - First Congregational Church, Guilford, CT - A celebration on his 45th Anniversary of Ordination, 1983. (Box 60)
      - Profile: Paul S. Minear: Finding the unexpected in the Bible, One World, 26, May 1977, p. 13. (Box 60)
      - Bibliography - A Publication Record, compiled by Paul S. Minear, n.d. (Box 60)
      - Bibliography of works, compiled by Raymond P. Morris (Box 60)
      - Paul S. Minear Publications, 1989. (Box 60)
  - Morris, Raymond P.
    See Record Group No. 80.
  - Muehl, E. William
    - The Dark Reflection of God, Sermon preached at Pennsylvania State Univ. Chapel, Nov 20, 1960. (Box 26)
    - Opinion: A Statement of Communication, Reflection, 85/1, Winter 1990, pp. 26-27. (Box 26)
    - The Specter of Economic Man, Address at annual luncheon of the Ministers and Missionaries Benefit Board of the American Baptist Convention, May 1963. (Box 26)
    - Three Favorite Heresies, Series of YDS Chapel lectures, n.d. (Box 26)
    - Bibliography of Published Works, compiled by Wm. Muehl, 1986 Jun 30. (Box 26)
    - Bill Muehl in Reflection: Opinion Columns Over Three Decades, 1990. (Box 26)
  - Napier, B. Davie
    - Elijah, Forerunner of the Great Prophets 1-18, n.d. (Box 26)
    - Creation, Covenant, Redemption. (Chapel Addresses, November 5, 6, 8, 1951) (Box 26)
  - Niebuhr, H. Richard
    - Christian Interpretation of History. (Typescript, Fall term, 1950, pp. 1-49). (Box 27)
    - The Gospel for a Time of Fears. (The Washington Federation of Churches and the School of Religion, Howard University; Sixth Annual Lecture Series, April, 1950). (Box 27)
    - The Illusions of Power. (The Pulpit: April, 1962, pp. 4-10). (Box 27)
    - Isolation and Cooperation in Theological Education. (Theological Education in America Bulletin #3, January, 1955). (Box 27)
    - Memo regarding the classification of books on ethics. c. 1934. (Box 27)
    - Prayers used in Niebuhr's lectures on Christian Ethics at YDS, n.d., pp. 1-7. (Box 27)
    - The Responsibility of the Church for Society. The Gospel, the Church and the World, Kenneth Scott Latourette, ed., (Harper & Brothers, 1946), pp. 111-133. (Box 27)
    - Sin and Forgiveness. (Lecture notes, 1951). (Box 27)
    - A Study of Theological Education in the United States and Canada. (Theological Education in America, Bulletin #1, 1954, April, pp. 1-7). (Box 27)
    - The Theological Basis for Pacifism. See Calhoun, Robert., n.d. (Box 27)
    - Theological Education and the World Mission of Christianity. (Conference of Theological Seminaries, 1929, pp. 3-11). (Box 27)
    - Towards a New Other-worldliness. Theology Today: 1944, pp. 78-87. (Box 27)
    - Towards the Reorganization of Theological Education. Theological Education in American Bulletin #5, c. 1954, pp. 1-10. (Box 27)
    - The Triad of Faith. (Andover Newton Bulletin, Convocation Issue, Oct. 1954) pp. 3-12. (Box 27)
    - Types of Christian Ethics. Mimeo., n.d. (Box 27)
    - Christian Ethics - lectures given at YDS (transcribed by Robert N. Yetter, M.Div. '53, 182 pp.), n.d. (Box 27)
    - Christian Ethics - lectures transcribed by H. Ellis Finger, Jr., Fall Quarter, 1939 and Winter Term, 1940. (Box 27)
    - The Hidden Church and the Churches in Sight. Religion in Life: Autumn 1978 (rpt. of 1945 article). (Box 27)
    - Bibliography of Works of HRN (compiled by Raymond P. Morris, revised 1964) (Box 27)
  - Noyce, Gaylord B.
    - Articles
      - The Appropriate Learning Moment. Church Educator, 4/9, Sep 1979, pp. 1,8. (Box 28)
      - Beware: Analogy Creeping In, Church Educator, 5/5, May 1980, pp. 1,19. (Box 28)
      - Bible Stories, Literalist and the Sunday School. The Christian Century, 101/14, Apr 25, 1984, p. 421. (Box 28)
      - Biophysical Reality and Spiritual Understanding: Our Evolving Paradigms. Quarterly Review, Summer, 1996, pp. 127-134. (Box 28)
      - Carrying...the Death of Jesus. Yale Divinity News, Mar 1962. (Box 28)
      - Christian Education and Evangelism. Church Educator, 3/10, Oct 1978, pp. 1,16. (Box 28)
      - A Covenant Consciousness. A.D. 1982 11/1, Jan, pp. 21-22. (Box 28)
      - The Dilemmas of Christians in Business. The Christian Century, Aug. 1981, pp. 802-804. (Box 28)
      - Education for Ministry: Theology, Preparedness, Praxis; Report of the Fifteenth Biennial Meeting of the Association for Profession Education for Ministry, 1978 (edited with Introduction by G. Noyce). (Box 28)
      - The Ethics of Evangelism. Christian Century, XCVI/32, Oct 10, 1979, pp. 973-6. (Box 28)
      - Further Reflections on Freedom Riding. Christianity and Crisis, XXI/14, Aug 7, 1961, pp. 147-8. (Box 28)
      - Give Us This Day Our Daily Bread. Church and Home, 4/4, Feb 15, 1967, pp. 24-25. (Box 28)
      - Has Ministry's Nerve Been Cut by the Pastoral Counseling Movement? Christian Century, Feb 1978, pp. 103 -106, 114 (Box 28)
      - Hooked and Whole Again. The Staley Distinguished Christian Scholar Lecture, Nov 14, 1981. (Box 28)
      - How Shall We Use the Bible Now? Christian Century, XCVI/12, Apr 4, 1979, pp. 370-373. (Box 28)
      - How to Use Biblical Criticism in Teaching. Church Educator, 9/6, Jun 1984, pp. 3-4. (Box 28)
      - Integration Takes New Forward Strides. United Church Herald, Oct 5, 1961, pp. 8-9, 23. (Box 28)
      - Join the World. International Journal of Religious Education, 43/3, Nov 1966, pp. 14-15. (Box 28)
      - Keeping Up with the World. Involvement, Jan-Feb, 1964, p. 8. (Box 28)
      - Killing the Goose That Gives Gold. Church Educator, 9/6, Jun 1984, pp. 3-4. (Box 28)
      - The Language of Public Prayer. Quarterly Review, Spring 1992, pp. 67-71. (Box 28)
      - Learning is a Happening. Spectrum - International Jour. of Rel. Education, 45/4, Jul/Aug 1969, pp. 8-9. (Box 28)
      - Make Way for Anger. United Church Herald, 8/4, Feb 15, 1965, pp. 22-23. (Box 28)
      - Mandate for the Mainline, The Christian Century, 8 November 1989, pp. 1017-19. (Box 28)
      - Methods of Reporting Experience In Ministry. A Seminar Paper for the Biennial Meeting of the Association for Theological Field Education, Jan 1977, Berkeley, California. (Box 28)
      - New Beginning. (Sermon) No Other Foundation, Vol. 15, No. 1, Summer 1994, pp. 39-42. (Box 28)
      - Our Children and the Work World. Church Educator, 4/7, Jul 1979, pp. 1,15. (Box 28)
      - The Pastor and Christian Education. Church Educator, Sep 1977, 2/9, pp. 1,12. (Box 28)
      - A People of Promise. The Disciple, 9/2, Jan 17, 1982, pp. 8-9. (Box 28)
      - Releasing the Life of the Church. Staley Distinguished Christian Scholar Lecture., n.d. (Box 28)
      - Releasing the Power of the Bible. Staley Distinguished Christian Scholar Lecture., n.d. (Box 28)
      - The Responsible Suburban Church. Thesis Theological Cassettes, the Speaker's Notebook of Quotes, Vol. 1/8 (Cassette tape)., n.d. (Box 28)
      - The Rhizome and the Rebel. Chapters 1-4, Preliminary 5-10, Work in Progress, 1990, pp. 1-144. (Box 28)
      - The Seasons of a Cleric's Life. Christian Century, 100/4, Feb 1983, pp. 90-93. (Box 28)
      - The Tensions of Our Calling. The Christian Ministry, pp. 18-21., n.d. (Box 28)
      - Why Are Churches So Prejudiced? Children's Religion, 23/12, Dec 1962, pp. 11-12. (Box 28)
      - Why We Don't Teach Them Morals, A.D. 1978, Mar, 7/3, p. 10. (Box 28)
      - Wider Work for Church Educators. Church Educator, 7/3, Mar 1982, pp. 1,10. (Box 28)
      - You're More Than a Cog in a Wheel. United Church Herald, 9/15, Sep 1966, pp. 9-10. (Box 28)
      - The Zeal of the Pastor. Minister's Quarterly, XVIII/3, Autumn 1962, pp. 9-11. (Box 28)
    - Reviews by Gaylord B. Noyce
      - Another Bicentennial Resource. Review of A Religious History of the American People, United Church Board for Homeland Ministries, 1976. (Box 28)
      - Houriet, Robert, Getting Back Together, The Review of Books and Religion, 1/9, Mid-May, 1972, p. 10. (Box 28)
      - Schall, James, Human Dignity and Human Numbers, The Review of Books and Religion, 1/7, Mid-March, 1972, p. 12. (Box 28)
  - Ogletree, Thomas W.
    - The Activity of Interpreting in Moral Judgment. JRE: 8, no.1 (1980), pp.1-25. (Box 30)
    - A Christological Assessment of Dipolar Theism. Journal of Religion: 47, no.2 (1967), pp.87-99. (Box 30)
    - The Ecclesial Context of Christian Ethics, The Annual of the Society of Christian Ethics. 17 pages., n.d. (Box 30)
    - The Eschatological Horizon of New Testment Social Thought. Annual of the Society of Christian Ethics, pp.55- 80., n.d. (Box 30)
    - Faith, Culture, and Power: Reflections on James H. Cone's Martin & Malcolm in America: Dream of Nightmare. (Box 30)
    - Review of God in Public: Political Theology Beyond Niebuhr, by William R. Coates. Journal of the American Academy of Religion. (Box 30)
    - The Gospel as Power: Explorations in a Theology of Social Change. The Iliff Review: 27, no.2 (1970), pp.41-58. (Box 30)
    - Power and Human Fulfillment. Pastoral Psychology: 22, no.216 (1971), pp.42-53. (Box 30)
    - The Public Witness of the Christian Communities: Reflections Based upon Ernst Troeltsch's Social Teaching of the Christian Churches. The Annual of the Society of Christian Ethics., n.d. (Box 30)
    - In Quest of a Common Faith: The Theological Task of the United Methodists. Quarterly Review: 8, no. 1 (1988), pp.43-53. (Box 30)
    - In Quest of Blessing: Feminist Wrestling with Scripture. Annual of the Society of Christian Ethics, pp.181-189., n.d. (Box 30)
    - Renewing Ecumenical Protestant Social Teaching. Justice and the Holy (1989), pp.338-405. (Box 30)
    - Responsibility: Essay for the fourth revised edition of the Encyclopedia of Bioethics. 1992. (Box 30)
    - The Secular City as a Theological Norm. pp.202-215., n.d. (Box 30)
    - Telling Our Story: Can Marketing Help Us? Society for the Advancement of Continuing Education for Ministry, January 7, 1994, pp.337-352. (Box 30)
    - Theological Ethics as a Hermeneutical Discipline: Biomedical Applications., n.d. (Box 30)
    - The Theology of Karl Barth: A Select Bibliography. Garrett Theological Seminary Library. 1966. (Box 30)
    - Values, Obligations, and Virtues: Approaches to BioMedical Ethics. JRE: 4, no.1 (1976), pp.105-130. (Box 30)
  - Outka, Gene
    - Agape: An Ethical Analysis, Japanese translation, 1999. (Box 29)
    - Agape: An Ethical Analysis, Korean translation, 1999. (Box 6)
    - Agapeistic Ethics. In A Companion to the Philosophy of Religion, eds. Philip L. Quinn and Charles Taliaferro (Oxford: Blackwell, 1997), pp. 481-488. (Box 29)
    - The Ascendancy of Ethics. Reflections, 89/1, Winter/Spring 1984, pp. 6-11. (Box 29)
    - Care Settings and Values: A Response, in Ethics of Health Care, Laurence R. Tencredi, ed., 1974, pp. 271-277. (Box 29)
    - Character, Conduct, and the Love Commandment, Virtue, Principles and Rules, n.d. (Box 29)
    - Character, Vision and Narrative, Religious Studies Review, 6/2, Apr 1980, pp. 110-118. (Box 29)
    - Comment on "Love in Contemporary Christian Ethics". Journal of Religious Ethics 26/2 (Fall, 1998), pp. 435-40. (Box 29)
    - Christian Ethics, in The Blackwell Companion to Religious Ethics, ed. William Schweiker (Oxford: Blackwell, 2005), pp. 197-203. (Box 29)
    - Dictionary Articles: "Kierkegaardian Ethics", "Love", "Respect for Persons", "Self-Realization", The Westminster Dictionary of Christian Ethics, 1986. (Box 29)
    - Discontinuity in the Ethics of Jacques Ellul. In Jacques Ellul: Interpretive Essays, C. G. Christians and J. M. Van Hook, eds., 1981, pp. 177-228. (Box 29)
    - Encyclopedia of Ethics articles on Kierkegaard; Love. Eds., Becker and Becker, 1992. (Box 29)
    - Equality and Individuality: Thoughts on Two Themes in Kierkegaard, The Journal of Religious Ethics, 10/2, Fall 1982, pp. 171-203. (Box 29)
    - Equality and Religiousness B (Mss) Read at 80th Annual Mtg. of the American Philosophical Association - Eastern Division, Dec 28, 1983. (Box 29)
    - Equality and the Fate of Theism in Modern Culture, reprinted from The Journal of Religion, Vol. 67, No. 3, July 1987. (Box 29)
    - The Ethics of Love and the Problem of Abortion: Second Annual James C. Spalding Memorial Lecture, School of Religion, The University of Iowa, 1999 Sep 27. (Box 29)
    - The Ethics of Human Stem Cell Research, in God and the Embryo: Religious Voices on Stem Cells and Cloning, ed. Brent Waters and Ronald Core-Turner (Washington, DC: Georgetown University Press, 2003) pp. 29-64. (Box 29)
    - Following at a Distance: Ethics and the Identity of Jesus, in Scriptural Authority and Narrative Interpretation, Garrett Green, 1987, pp. 144-160. (Box 29)
    - Foreward, in Islamic Ethics of Life: Abortion, War, and Euthanasia, ed. Jonathan E. Brockopp (Columbia: University of South Carolina Press, 2003) pp. vii-x. (Box 29)
    - God as the Subject of Unique Veneration: A Response to Ronald M. Green. Journal of Religious Ethics, 21/2 (Fall, 1993), pp. 211-215. (Box 29)
    - The Individual Person as of Supreme Worth: Remarks on a Moral, Political and Religious Idea (Mss) Jul 28, 1983. (Box 29)
    - Introduction. Augustinanism and Common Morality. Prospects for a Common Morality, Gene Outka and John P. Reeder Jr., eds., (Princeton University Press, 1993), pp. 3-28; pp. 114-148. (Box 29)
    - Introduction (with John P. Reeder, Jr.) in Religion and Morality, Reeder and Outka, eds., 1973, pp. 1-32. (Box 29)
    - Keep Yale Divinity School Where It Is. New York Times editorial 1996 Jun 22. (Box 29)
    - Kierkegaard, Soren and Love. Entries to a larger reference work, pp. 678-681; pp. 742-751. (Box 29)
    - On Harming Others, Interpretation, 34/4, Oct 1980, pp. 381-393. (Box 29)
    - The Particularist Turn in Theological and Philosophical Ethics. In Christian Ethics: Problems and Prospects, Lisa Sowle Cahill and James F. Childress, eds., (Pilgrim Press) pp.93-118. (Box 29)
    - Situation Ethics, in Routledge Encyclopedia of Philosophy, ed. Edward Craig (London and New York: Routledge, 1998), vol. 8, pp. 798-799. (Box 29)
    - The Protestant Tradition and Exceptionless Moral Norms in Moral Theology Today: Certitudes and Doubts, D. G. McCarthy, ed., 1984, pp. Situation Ethics. In Routledge Encyclopedia of Philosophy, ed. Edward Craig (New York:Routledge, 1998), vol. 8, pp. 798-799. (Box 29)
    - Situationsethik. In Theologische Realenzyklopadie, vol. 31, ed. Gerhard Muller (Berlin: Verlag Walter de Gruytor), translated into German by D. Schopsdau, pp. 337-342., n.d. (Box 29)
    - Social Justice and Equal Access to Health Care. In Ethics in Medicine: Historical Perspectives and Contemporary Concerns, S. J. Reiser, A. J. Dyck, W. J. Curran, eds., 1977, pp. 585-593. (Box 29)
    - Social Justice and Equal Access to Health Care (Revised), Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 18/2 Winter, 1975, pp. 185-203. (Box 29)
    - Theocentric Agape and the Self: An Asymmetrical Affirmation in Response to Colin Grant's Either/Or. In Journal of Religious Ethics, Spring, 1996, pp. 35-42. (Box 29)
    - Tribute to Hans Frei. In booklet from memorial service of 1988 Sep 22. (Box 29)